

FILIP GOČ DESIGNER OF LEARNING EXPERIENCES

filip@imade3d.com linkedin.com/in/filipgoc @filipgoc on Twitter

Intro

I design and run learning experiences and curricula often involving modern technologies both on-line and off-line. I have also designed an award-winning 3D Printer. My approaches are steeped in cognitive science of learning, design thinking, game-inspired learning, and both constructionist and constructivist theories. I believe in curiosity, combining liberal arts with digital fabrication, and open-ended, student-centered education.

I am DIY aficionado and a tinkerer, both as a professional and as a hobbyist. I like the smell of freshly cut wood and of ink laid on a paper, yet, most of the time, I make digital things. Digital photography, movie editing, sound recording, and the like. I sometimes play with code, and it may or may not end up online.

Skills

Education & Tech

Instructional design and curriculum design, online and offline teaching, hands-on education, design thinking, constructionist learning, educational game design, MOOCs, iterative design processes.

English

Native-like with a soft spot for precision and clarity

Media Production

Videography, shooting and editing (Premiere Pro, Vegas, Final Cut Pro). Analog and Digital Photography (Lightroom, Photoshop). Graphics (Illustrator, InDesign, Inkscape). Audio (Audition, Audacity).

Czech

Native with a soft spot for archaic and unusual phrases

"Making"

3D Printer Development, RepRap, Slicing Development (Simplify3D, Cura, Slic3r), CAD (Fusion360, TinkrCAD, OpenSCAD, Onshape), Arduino (Marlin), lasercutting, CNC, lathe, Git.

French

Intermediate with a soft spot for being understood

Education

Harvard Graduate School of Education

Master of Education: Technology, Innovation, and Education

2012-2013

Associate of Student Advisory Board | Winner of Harvard XDesign Education Challenge

University of Virginia Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Sciences

2010-2012

Focus in Digital Humanities, New Media, and Cognitive Psychology | Dean's List

Northern Virginia Community College Associate Degree

2009-2010

Presidential Scholar and Dean's List | Award of High Academic Achievement

Projects

IMADE₃D, LLC Captain of Design and Education

2015-present

Co-founded a startup to teach general public, teachers, and students to assemble and use DIY 3D Printers - as a learning experience. Co-designed 3D Printer "JellyBOX" from scratch, optimizing the design for ease of assembly, maintenance and learning. I modeled the design in Fusion360, AutoCAD, and Illustrator, and collaborated on setting up manufacturing in rural Virginia. I also developed the IMADE3D educational concept of Hands-on Builds, created a DIY online documentation (Dozuki, Docsify,Discourse), shot and edited instructional videos, designed and administered our web, interfaced with partners, and managed the online community. JellyBOX has been awarded "Best for Schools" by Make Magazine in 2017 and 2019.

www.imade3d.com

Design 101 MOOC, Iversity Community Meta-Manager and Lead

2014

Lead an international community of -40 volunteers to manage a vibrant community of 40,000 students (about 10,000 active) in Iversity's Design 101 MOOC. Imagined and spearheaded ways to make this technologically and humanly possible. Heavily experimented with social and communication media (Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Google+, Hangouts, Slack, forum, email...) to keep the students engaged.

http://iversity.org/en/courses/design-101-or-design-basics

2014

Together with EDS founder Jess, developed and ran a 2-day hackathon in design thinking that put together educators, students, policy makers, and designers to design educational policy. Co-designed the website and print materials, shot video interviews with 'inspiring experts' (including the Massachusetts Secretary of Education, dr. Malone), developed scoring rubric, planned the activities... and anything else that was needed.

http://edudesignshop.mit.edu

HyperStudio at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology Research Intern to Visualize Digital Annotations

2013

In collaboration with HyperStudio, designed and coded interactive visualizations of users' paths through the readings with Processing and D3.js, using annotation data from HyperStudio's Annotation studio. Additionally, built a case study to optimize the UX and streamline the website. Presented these stories on "Temporal Aspect of Annotating" at "Convergence @Harvard" conference.

Experience

Emerson College School of Communication

Human-Centered Design Facilitator & Senior Project Manager

2013-2015

Over the course of a year, lead a cross-departmental, diverse group of faculty to re-thing and re-align the structure and programming of the entire School of Communication in the spirit of design thinking. Analysed the ed-tech space, and provided resources and activities to have the faculty explore and experience current communication and educational technology trends. Designed and managed online spaces to share findings and interact asynchronously. Run an internal mini-conference on technological trends including a design thinking workshop.

Emerson College

Teaching Assistant for Communication Management

2015

Provided feedback and guidance on graduate students' final year's Communication Management projects. Managed class's Canvas site including forum and submissions and google docs integrations. Secured video recordings of sessions, and provided general IT support. Led classes on various subjects.

HarvardX (Harvard branch of EdX) Comparative MOOC-ologist

2014

A part of a team assembled to compare and contrast MOOC courses from various providers, and identify the best course design and community management practices. Produced an internal document outlining the state of the art and proposing innovative approaches to teaching online across disciplines.

University of Liverpool Laureate Online Courses Instructional Designer & Curriculum Writer

2013-2014

Worked with an international team of content experts to re-design and re-write existing online courses in an MBA program to fit into a new school-wide pedagogical model aimed at increasing interactivity and students' collaboration.

HFR Veritas Education

Curriculum Designer and Content Expert

2014

Co-created curricula for after-school programs in Creative Problem Solving and Critical thinking for a local start-up in Shanghai, China. Reviewed and compiled existing literature and trends in teaching creativity. Spearheaded human-centered design practices in developing the coursework - held multiple sessions with a selection of future Chinese students to test activities and align the curriculum with the needs and expectations of the regional audience. Delivered both instructional activities for students, and teaching manual for instructors.

Center for Talented Youth of Johns Hopkins University Teaching Assistant of Cognitive Psychology

2011-2012

Prepared and taught college level lessons on various topics of Cognitive Psychology to class of 15 gifted teenagers. Supervised students' learning with an interactive suite of cognitive psychology experiments. Supplied students with lab report templates and critical thinking question, and provided constructive feedback on performance.

Northern Virginia Community College Writing Center ESOL and English Writing Tutor

2010

Held one-on-one tutoring sessions with college students of all English proficiencies (including native speakers). Worked with students to improve both their grammar and writing style. Specialized on American academic writing structure and style.